RICARDO GRANDA VASQUEZ

+34652645476 | info@ricardograndavasquez.com

PROFESSI ONAL SUMMARY

Over the past 5 years I have been working with React, JavaScript and Typescript, developing libraries and SPA that incorporate different Micro Front Ends. I am committed to collaboration and solution oriented problem solving.

As a Full Stack Developer, I worked with PHP language and frameworks such as Laravel and Symfony, along with Relational Databases. My expertise also extends to Agile methodologies, Version Control Systems and CI/CD processes. I enjoy learning new technologies.

WORK HISTORY

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Kuorum | Barcelona | April 2023 - June 2023

- Improved the quality of React, TypeScript, and CSS (SASS) by conducting code analysis.
- Successfully delivered projects on time, following Agile Methodologies.
- Developed efficient and reusable code with React.
- Enabled accurate project tracking and reporting in GitHub and Jira.
- Enhanced website navigation with clear user experience (UX) mapping.
- Facilitated code reviews and pair programming sessions to ensure production of high quality code.
- Collaborated with web designers to align with intended visual design.
- Stack: Tailwind, Typescript, React, Git, Agile Methodologies, AWS, Jest (testing)

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

DBS Bank - Singapore | Barcelona | February 2022 - December 2022

- Developed efficient and reusable code libraries.
- Managed software lifecycle from concept to execution.
- Wrote clean and well-tested code for various Micro Front Ends.
- Implemented system testing and validation guidelines.
- Generated reports on programming project specifications, activities, and developments.
- Verified and resolved bug reports and issues.
- Trained teams to develop skills using React library and hooks.
- Optimised frontend performance through clean coding practices.
- Facilitated code reviews and pair programming sessions to ensure production of high quality code.
- Stack: React, TypeScript, Redux, Redux Saga, Redux Thunk, Unit Testing, Confluence, Git, Jenkins, Agile, Kanban.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Green Power Monitor - DNV | Barcelona - Remote | July 2019 - February 2022

- Performed manual and automated testing to ensure stability of React Libraries, achieving a test coverage of 75%.
- Collaborated with UX designers and Product Owners to create cohesive products with Agile Methodologies.
- Wrote clean, well-tested code for React using Ant Design.
- Improved quality of React and CSS by conducting code analysis and recommending changes to policies and procedures.
- Updated custom libraries to different React versions, ensuring compatibility with TypeScript and dependencies.
- Verified and resolved bug reports and issues.
- Developed algorithms and flowcharts to create new software and systems.
- Facilitated code reviews and pair programming sessions to foster the creation of high-quality code.
- Stack: React, TypeScript, Jest, Unit Testing, Confluence, Git, Azure DevOps Tools, Agile, Kanban, Lodash.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Tappx | Barcelona, Spain | July 2019 - July 2021

- Optimized user experience by ensuring development of well-structured frontend and backend code.
- Actively drove continuous improvement by staying up to date with latest changes in software development.
- Created databases, data entry systems, and web forms.
- Developed websites with HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript skills.
- Collaborated with web designers to align with intended visual design.
- Developed and tested REST APIs, ensuring effective response to wide variety of requests.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Confluence, Git, Jenkins, PHP, Laravel, Tableau API, Vue.js, jQuery.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Nük Studio | Barcelona, Spain | January 2016 - July 2017

- Managed databases using SQL skills.
- Developed frontend and backend for mobile and web applications.
- Created websites with HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript skills.
- Applied SEO techniques to improve Google rankings and engagement.
- Tech Stack: PHP, Laravel, jQuery, WordPress, Bootstrap, HTML, Git, Lodash, Foundation.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Alfil Communication Company | Madrid, Spain | December 2011 - December 2015

- Built site specific interfaces for navigation, data management, and e-commerce requirements.
- Collaborated with clients and designers to develop robust and functional platforms.
- Created custom websites by leveraging HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript skills.

- Delivered front-end and back-end development for web applications.
- Tech Stack: PHP, Codeigniter, Dingo (PHP library), WordPress, Bootstrap, HTML, Git, Lodash, CSS.

SKILLS

- React
- React testing library
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- HTML/ CSS
- Sass

- Git,
- Object-oriented PHP
- Laravel
- Symfony
- CI/CD.

EDUCATION

EXPERT Programming Courses

Pluralsight

Barcelona / Spain | January 2020 - Current

EXPERT Relational Databases

London Education Center

Madrid | July 2014 - December 2014

EXPERT Structural Programming Languages

London Education Center

Madrid / Spain | July 2014 - December 2014

EXPERT Operation Systems and Applications

London Education Center

Madrid / Spain | July 2014 - December 2014

EXPERT Mobile Application with Mongo, Express, Angular and Node

Trazos

Madrid / Spain | January 2014 - May 2014